[Music]
Couple other than that, now I have to go
to the middle
page of the book, Bandit, Matteo Carlo planning,
what's so amazing about it, okay, so there's a
technique that people have used,
people who typically talk about Matteo
Carlo methods, I use something called role-playing,
so the idea behind role-playing is the
following, so I have a heuristic way of
selecting action, I'm trying to solve the
problem, so I have some heuristic way of
selecting action, okay, so what do I do? I come
to a particular
state, right, so I use the
heuristic, right, and select action and run
multiple trials from there, so I use what's every
heuristic, I have I
select and run multiple
trials, so what is this heuristic, you can think
of it like policy, policy, what's
mapping from station, first just
policy, I use the policy, and run select
action, and then  What I want is to look at
the different outcomes that come from
running a particular
ristic. Then I pick an
action to give me the best
possible expected
outcome.
Make
sense. Let's try it again. OK, if you have
determinism, then what you should do is probably select an
action probable at the
beginning. And then run your rotic. OK, so I
start from some state. Let's say I pick
action a1. Then let's say I can pick action a2.
Then there are two actions I can pick. The ristic
will suggest something. Let's say I pick action a1
first. And then I
run my policy p-a likewise. Pick action a2. Run
my policy
p-a likewise. OK, then I take the average
value. I get here. I take the average
value. I get here. No, I take the action which ever gives me the better
average
value. Right, so this might not be action
given by pi, and it might be action given
by pi. We don't know right.
So all I'm saying is given any.
Policy pie I can do a lot of work and
I'm guaranteeing you what policy or
acting role pie will be at least
good and on better than time than
role action of policy pie will be
better than pie
generating multiple tasks using pie right it looks like
rolling out the
policy is something like this right but this
precedes all of these things so this kind of
role idea of ​​execute right this is nothing to do with
first of all nothing to do
with MD
piece right so it could be any kind of game that
you are playing it could be adversarial
setting it could be anything right I talk nothing about
value function right I talk nothing about
returns nothing precedes all of that okay in
fact not a question of
policy role a question pie could come from any rigid I don't have any
notion of time as well so what role
a question gives you is always
The performance of pi, do I can improve it if it doesn't babble, don't get better policy, very
high like optimum,
think about it, it's very much like doing one
step of policy
improvement, right now, don't do one step of
policy improvement over pi, if you think about it,
right, so what do I do here, this is essentially
evaluation of pi, I did evaluation of pi,
specific for starting
from one step after a, right,
so I just did policy evaluation of
pa, and I was greedy with repeq, to
policy evaluation, so this is called roll out execution, follow pa, until you
reach the goal state,
or follow pa, until you reach the goal state, or
how many iterations should I run from
a1, this depends, now I want to tell me what it depends
on, in the uti, the leaves with the
arms, and you run from the root to the in each
iteration you run from the root to the leaves that is
you are following one arm at each time
step and or each of the interior nodes you
have that upper bound term that you
maximize you are confusing two many
things but you are gone or so there was nothing we
follow at one time step we follow one that means one pi till we reach the end you are saying that here we are
following many we are saying only one pi no no but we are doing many
tragedies
or there it is one tragedy
at each time stay we are following one or so we will come to that right
i am not talking or
not talking to you about your tragedies just ask
me questions on what i have told you so far this
is not a uc tree this is just
roll outs i am just talking to you about roll outs
taking your
tragedies when was how many time should i run two
tact, of course, but how much how much tell
me it depends, either directly
or
indirectly, exactly so closer together, so precisely right. If
the system is deterministic and
pi is deterministic, one trajectory is enough. If
the system is very stable, or if pi is deterministic, then
you probably need to run the law of
trajectory. If all kinds of random things are happening, then you probably need to
run the law of trajectory. And if pi itself is a very stable policy, then you can run
the law of trajectory. Okay, so it depends on the variable in the sampling process. If the variance in the samples you draw is very small, it's sufficient to run a small number of times. Or any other factor that will determine this tree length, then should tree length be the
determining
factor?
Equally accurate, then not very easily, can be a
factor in any other way.
Computation rate, so how much computation
time do you have to spare between every
This is a very practical consideration and you have to actually be
cognizant of it
so the length will affect your efficiency but also at the end of your
computation you have so the
longer the term the further you can generate incrementally the longer the term the more
you want to generate because it increases
the variable but you have to do
the opposite so either way you're cutting down the
term here
exactly so don't go all the way to the end
right stop somewhere in between
depending on how much time you have how
much computation you can spare for this and how much how many
variables are there in the system
okay so if you can find a good ristic that tells you how
much more it is going to cost if you
run till the end you can use that
ristic as the terminal cost right remember now we
talk about why we call value
iteration dynamic programming  So you can
think of the value as a terminal cost,
right? So we have a one-step problem, and then we have
a terminal cost like that. Or you will have
a mini-step problem, and you have a
terminal cost, right? So what should be the
terminal cost? What natural terminal cost
for us to
use is the value function. Right, if you have an amount
of the value function, you can use set as the
terminal cost. So far, I didn't talk
about the need for a value function. I can do
rollouts. Just given a policy, I don't need
a value function, but the reason for
using a value function with rollouts is if
the text is very long, the variable is very
high, right? So, if the text is a small number of samples, you can take it. It's going to be
self-
defeating because larger variables have the ability to
take more samples. So, and then get around the
people started using the amount of the value function.
So, you have to have a value function.  Can I start doing something
clever good
so some sro was look a peripheral thing in the
rrl community for while I in fact never
started teaching this course I used to give a
hand out from dynamic programming book no rrl because it was
not covered in the rrl
textbook so I used to take xeroxes of it well as was before
every textbook ever
printed became freely available on the
internet so I used to give photocopies of the
few pages discuss rrl policy rrl gave it out
to the class to read about rrl policy a thing like that
and then things changed dramatically kli when
my god I thought his name was harder
to
pronounce well chaba and another Hungarian with
hard prose name came up with something called
upper confidence trees you see trees
okay so you see trees at the heart use a roll
out like idea right but they also use the
notion of value  Functions and upper
confidence bounds we saw from bandits so they
use the notion of up UC upper confidence
bound bandits UCB one specifically they
use the idea from UB and if you rebar I told you there are many
variations of UCB they
use a very simple one the UB and then married it with what they called
Monte Carlo tree
search so I'm going to explain Monte
Carlo tree search first and then I'll tell you what they did to get
UT and it
turns out to be one of the most powerful
planning algorithms that people use in the
literature okay I should
explain what I mean by planning because it's
unique to
Rin so I'll introduce this difference between
learning and planning into the community so
learning in you try to solve MDP with
no a of
parameters it online it's completely simple
driven and so so  First, in planning, you have some kind
of specification of a model, right,
and you use the model some how to solve your
problem. So, of these Monte Carlo methods, if
you use a sample model, remember we talk about
sample models and full models, right, I use
simulation models and sample models, it comes under
the regime of planning because you're using a
model, okay, so what we talk about can either be a
planning and a learning algorithm,
depending on how you draw your samples, okay, if you
draw your samples from a real system, then it becomes a
learning algorithm, if you're
drawing samples from a simulation model, then it becomes
a planning algorithm, right, but there are other
methods that use the model more integrally, more
integrally, in their method. As opposed to what we've spoken about so far, there are many Monte
Carlo planning methods,
so we'll talk about Monte Carlo tree
search. Let me see if I can make
my guess.  Need to get my
glasses
[music]
Sorry, I had much variation
today, but I
put it down to variation in the system,
so I go and read the paper, my
subroutine of this routine, so this is a search
function, a write function, a search, start
some state and some data at this, it's going to be called a rate, so I have some kind
of depth
to search, I'll
search some data, a search, and I start by
checking this terminal
state, terminal state, I just return
zero, in a simple case, I return the terminal return zero, in this case, the terminal return
zero, as I'm going to return zero, or I'm going to
return zero
[music]
OK, and I check, I return something, let's return some
state, let's return some state, let's return that, and then after further
processing, write, then I evaluate
what ever the state is, what ever the
value of the state, I will return that
value, this is like the terminal cost  That's what we
spoke about right if I stop here I will
use the value of the state as the terminal
cost right so we will evaluate the state some how
and we will return the value okay so
what is next okay now it is not a leaf
state okay it is not a terminal state so that means
we are somewhere here so we are not here we are not here so that means we are somewhere here right
so summer there what do I do I
select an action right so how do I select an
action
based on
the or the heuristic function so what ever was the
original heuristic function given to
me I select an action based on that
heuristic function right I select an action based
on the right function then I will take
one step I will simulate the
trajectory so Ashley what I am doing here I simulate
the trajectory right I find
what the next state is I also find what is the  I get a
reward for taking that
action
so well if you can actually behave in the
real world go ahead and behave in the real
world but how are you going to reset you back
to that thing and generate another story right so if you want to do something like this
you better have a
simulation model right so this is the you need to have a
simulation model okay this point I miss but
you need to have a simulation model yes I have to get
multiple actions starting from here if it's in the real
world to roll robot bacon run anke then catch it put it back no no no
playing
games it's like playing with the kid right so the
kid plays some moves and no no no I want to take it back after
four
moves so so I'm like that right anyway so
you do the next step and you get the reward
based on your simulation model and then what do you do
you take your return right or treat it with
reward right and  Then what you do is gamma
times search from the next stage.
Essentially, you are going to trace the total path
until you reach
a terminal state. If you reach the terminal state,
you keep popping back the reward.
If you reach the leaf state, you
reach the depth. If you are going to cut
off and reach the terminal state, what you do is at the
point where you keep passing the rewards
back up the calling stack. So, this recursive
call, you keep popping the reward back up. So, this
summation, it finally finishes computing the function. It will have
returned the complete return and the truncated return. We will return the corrected return and the truncated
return. So, if we come
to the stopping condition, then if we sum the condition
of all functions, then we have to return it, then we take the
corrected return and the truncated
return. So, if we
return it, then we update the value
of state and action i.
From the value of state and action i, we
take the total.  Return and death at this action was
taken from the
state okay so it was death portent again the rate
terminal state returned zero very
top no date
[music]
cand that how many
states you've got through
okay and we do
need so it's not
making any mark as here so
so closure I'm to the end right so the
value function will be
different right if I take if I have five more
steps to go and I only take
five steps I have a longer direction to
go right so I need to maintain the
distinction the value function right I'm still not to use the way I told you about this right so when we have a
fixed
horizon the world is going to stop in
at time t equal to 10 and something like that right so if
you are one step away from that
you will behave in a different way if you are
100 steps away from that you will behave
in a different way so I'm just giving you
the number of steps that you've taken so that if
you want to specialize your value function
based on the number of steps that you have taken
you could do so
okay but there is another reason for carrying the
depth run but for the before we get to that okay before I talk about
upper conference
bonds and stuff like that so the Monte Carlo tree you can carry the whole thing
for another you can throw the data
in update so you need the data or so you can throw the data
in update if you're taking everything is
completely done
okay
or whatever you are in the system right so you don't
need the data in the
case or but only in the previous one you need the
left leaf
or or or fine so this if you call this you
call it with your initial state and depth  of
zero rate so here you call it you call it
width and depth of zero okay and you could call this
multiple times
firm every time you call it
nominal and it gives you a return curve spring
to every time you call it nominal and it gives you a return curve spring to every time you call it nominal and then you can
choose your best action based on
the return you are getting firm there okay so firm you
run this multiple
times
take return again and again a firm choose best
action or choose action or policy
exploration then your first policy
exploration then it becomes issue
and how your best
action is each
state basedly or limited to which action was each one
stood and up each next government hast
value or
pension and multiple times you can choose your action
using the value function
right you have to remember what we covered already
so I said how to  Recover a policy given a
value
function given how to behave gracefully with
respect to a value function not a q
function v function so you could do that and you
could modify this whole thing to give you q
function instead
of v function how will you modify this to give
you
q
okay great
so this is the basic structure of
what is called a Matteo Carlo tree search
okay and depending on how you select
actions right so you can get different codes
of algorithms out of it and the most
popular one is called yes trees right where the
select action is going to use
an upper confidence bound like formulation so
I'm going to look at the expected
reward for taking an
action plus a term for the confidence
bound right so what is the term going to
depend on the
number of times you pull the term anything else
auspicious
[music]
factor factor then how much  So there's one
magic constant that comes in there okay it's what they needed to actually help prove some
results okay and they had one some
bound not magic
constant all what bound was by or
soar by
magically like your see but rate expression l be the same except
of just having the root
of
b
rate you to beat or bit by or soar what you did or id or some
magic constant c p time rate l bake
so y select action so selecting
action rm di fix pi so what y do you look
at the current added value function for this action
add some r bake
depends on the problem
solving okay so the higher the vari ability in
the
system the larger the CP has to be rate because you want to
explore more higher
vari ability in the system the larger the CP
will be okay this is something y typically a  Datum
epically, some band, how large is it to search
and so on, so fourth, I can get the
numbers, letters, but you do this series, plus the k
value,
rate, and then you select the action according to that, and then
go back and pick your best
action, so what if you're in to, you have to
explore, exploit the problem, right, you need to
explore many different
actions in this action selection space, so then you
go back and select your best action, or
select every action of an action, and keep
exploring, all the time by one, you go back, you will not have, you would have
wasted too many
samples, suppose I give you like 1000 samples
that you can take, you would like to explore, the
more
promising you are going to be, you are going to split your budget too much, right,
across all of these things, so
doing it, like exploration, gives you
much more focused learning, right, so just like we have
in  The UCB case gives you much
more focused learning. Okay, and this was one very
elegant way of converting a
solution for
solving the full real problem into a linear solution.
You
need a simulation model. You need a simulation model
to be able to do this. If you have simulation tools, you
can do dynamic style planning and get into many
cases. You can come up with some kind of
rough simulation
model and you can get into some kind of
linear solution methods. And in many robotic
situations, if you have simulators, it turns out to be very
robust planning and get into a lot of linear solution methods. Now, I
like to use UCB
in my processes.
Okay, any question on this,
so be putting up the paper for you to read. I will
not set the paper to read. Okay, so
most of the lectures, most of the writings are a little hard to
penetrate.
Okay,
lectures are
not linear, but they are  Lc video linear blue
page ner
leo classic
link sony
telling the links then le one
cyborg nut yer nay
under something ok yer nap some
live demo ya
live holi y understand more now and
please see u see u ask this if you can get up to date
representation for the
value function can behave well in the action
dimension then it
work and come down to one aspect of the
letter in something talk about using this part
representation or asking if it work if you have
parameter representation so you can do this
update value right so you can update actual
set of parameters represent the function just like we talk about
in reinforce rate
update the policy parameter you need value
function parameterize like that then you can get up to a bit more
condition can behave well of value
[music]
fashion some
bon o  In the context of this action, I'm
good when I think about it. So, I'm the thing I've taken.
So, this is the
number of times I've basically taken this action. So, basically, the number
of times I've taken this
action. And this is your depth. So, the reason you need to have depth every where is right and this is the number
of times you've taken the
action. The total number
of times you've taken this action
is the total number of times you've taken this action. So, this will be the total number of
times you've taken
that action. So, this will be the total number of times you've taken this action. So, this will be the total number of times you've taken this action. So, this is ...
This will work in
the continuous action space for this so we have to
figure out how to make it work
okay fine let's set okay we can move on to the
next
topic so at the end of chapter five so
we're starting chapter six but chapter
five in the second edition of the book is one
additional section okay so they talk about some
of the recent work prime been done by Rich Sun
and group
n n n trang to reduce variance in Monte
Carlo sampling so one thing they talk about is
you
really have long task right but you have small
discount
factor from gamma lock and something so the
contribution the return of the subsequent
term is going to die down very
quickly right so you really don't need to
maintain this full product right you could get away with doing something that is
truncated right
im looking at p e x b q a
right I don't have to do the whole product I
can do something  Truncated so how do you do that
in a principled manner and give some kind
of guarantee about convergence and stuff like that rat he gives a very very high level
quick discussion about that in the last
section in the chapter in the book right so again
you can't
for information ra that means I will not ask
questions on it
in the exam is what it means if you want to know what it
translates
to two other things we a ask you to read w I't say
r for information so dos r fer
[music]
[applause]
game